A Guide to the Memorabilia FA437
Rockefeller Archive Center
Memorabilia
undated
Rockefeller Archive Center
FA437
680 Cubic Feet Extent is approximate.
Conditions Governing Access
All inquiries to view memorabilia items require permission from RAC, and advanced notice of up to one week. Individual items may be restricted from scholarly access at the discretion of RAC. Please see RAC Head of Archival Services for details.
Arrangement
The Memorabilia collection is arranged by subject, in 10 series primarily based on central Rockefeller family members. Each individual object has been assigned a unique number 1-8999.
Series 1: Nelson A. Rockefeller (NAR) (objects #1 – 999) Series 2: John D. Rockefeller Sr. (JDR SR) (objects #1000 – 1999) Series 3: John D. Rockefeller Jr. (JDR JR) (objects #2000-2999) Series 4: John D. Rockefeller 3rd (JDR 3RD) (objects #3000-3999) Series 5: Laurance S. Rockefeller (LSR) (objects #4000-4999) Series 6: David Rockefeller (DR) (objects #5000-5999) Series 7: Rockefeller University (objects #6000-6999) Series 8: Harold P. Fabian (objects #7000-7999) Series 9: Rockefeller Foundation Decorations (objects #8000-8999) Series 10: Ford Foundation (object # associated with RAC accession number).
Any Rockefeller family members/interests not specifically listed above or relating to the Rockefeller family in general, as well as miscellaneous/unidentified objects, are included with the JDR SR series, #1000-1999.
The objects themselves show evidence of various attempts at organization by RAC over the years; many have numbers and inscriptions from past cataloguing which may refer to their original collection information. No new stickers were added to the objects, but some stickers have been left on items rather than risk damage to the item through removal of the (inappropriately glued) labels. When possible, pieces have been identified with acid-free label tags on strings. A majority of the documents have been labeled in pencil on the back of the paper, and are also in labeled folders or envelopes. Albums and books have ID hangtags, and foam or plastic-wrapped items are marked on their exterior wrapping.
On the NAR material, the rectangular stickers with rounded corners have the correct, current identification number. Any stickers, labels or numbers that don’t correspond to the new four-digit ID system are irrelevant, inactive and discontinued. Most labels are written with the initials of the relevant family member (i.e. “SR #1010” or “LSR #4004”), but some may just have the four-digit ID number (#3020).
Custodial History
In 2009, the RAC began an effort to expand and enhance physical and intellectual control of the mixed-media artifacts and commemorative objects found throughout many of the archival collections. A large volume of non-document materials had already been separated from the body of various archival collections and stored in an attic, which, over the years, was sporadically inventoried. In a previous cataloguing project, all of the Nelson Rockefeller (NAR) memorabilia was described and numbered consecutively, with about 985 pieces. Materials relating to John D. Rockefeller Sr. and John D. Rockefeller Jr. were both given separate numbering systems, while the rest of the Rockefeller members’ items had never been inventoried. The 2009 project, adopted the unique numbering of the NAR series (#1-999) and added the other major Rockefeller family figures, and small volumes of memorabilia from the Rockefeller University, Rockefeller Foundation, Ford Foundation and other RAC archival holdings, in subsequently numbered series (see Arrangement note). All other previous numbering is inactive and discontinued.
Scope and Contents
Encompassing a wide range of media and styles, including plaques, paintings, photographs, textiles, costumes, and audiovisual materials, the memorabilia primarily documents over 100 years of history of the Rockefeller family and several of their philanthropic endeavors including the Rockefeller University and Rockefeller Foundation. The collection also consists of memorabilia from the Ford Foundation and Harold P. Fabian papers.
A majority of the items can be traced to a specific Rockefeller family member, but not necessarily to a definitively verifiable provenance or originating collection, so a subject-based arrangement was adopted.
Glossary
A controlled vocabulary was introduced to simplify the naming of various formats within the Memorabilia collection. The glossary below provides this terminology, which lists generalized definitions as pertaining only to the Memorabilia.
Glossary
A/V – A limited selection of audio-visual materials.
BOOK - Published books, privately published books and commemorative books.
CITATION - Honors conferred or bestowed, in the form of a document indicating or symbolizing the award or remuneration. Citations are not mounted items, but sometimes accompany a medal or commemorative object.
COMMEMORATIVE - Miscellaneous items produced, issued, or worn to honor a person, event, or occasion which are not unto themselves specific awards; includes paperweights, sculptures, shovels, flags, etc; also includes most campaign-related materials.
CORRESPONDENCE - Any forms of addressed and written communication sent and received, including letters, postcards, memorandums, notes, telegrams, or cables.
DIPLOMA - Certificates, degrees and honorary degrees bestowed from universities and educational institutions.
DOCUMENT - Any paper item that is not a citation or correspondence, including printed items, books, pamphlets, newspaper, etc.
MEDAL - Small metal decorations and ornaments created with a commemorative or honorary purpose; any award that is not a plaque or document; often but not always refers to ornaments worn on the individual, such as royal appointments or pins which might hang on ribbons for the neck or shoulder.
MEMORIAL - Any memorial objects that are not specifically applicable to other categories.
MISCELLANEOUS - Any object or document not included in previous categories and/or lacking accompanying information, including art.
PICTURE - Any non-photographic, two-dimensional image, including paintings, cartoons, blueprints, etc.
PHOTOGRAPH - Any photographically-reproduced image, whether an original or a duplicate. Photographs may be positive or negative, opaque or transparent, printed on any medium.
PLAQUE - Any mounted award, citation, or honors conferred, sometimes paired with a token which relates to the document.
- Nelson A. Rockefeller, 1
  - certificate of recognition, International Narcotics Enforcement, 1966 August 27; 17" x 14", see #77 same source (Object 1)
    General note
    PLAQUE
    Conditions Governing Access note
    All inquiries to view memorabilia items require permission from RAC, and advanced notice of up to one week. Individual items may be restricted from scholarly access at the discretion of RAC. Please see RAC Head of Archival Services for details.
  - certificate of recognition, Southern Italy Educational Fund, 1990 October 26; 13.75" x 16.75" (Object 2)
    CITATION
  - certificate of recognition as Honorary State Chairman, from the USO, 1970 April 14; 12" x 15", see #181, DEFRAMED (Object 3)
  - congratulatory note to NAR in envelope w/ engraved gold plate, 2 stamps, $1 coin from Watson F. Pharo, NJ, 14" x 14" (Object 4)
    COMMEMORATIVE
  - citation, NY Society of Professional Engineers, 1968 June 7; 15 x 12 (Object 6)
  - certificate of admission to the Empire State Society from the Sons of the American Revolution, 1965 July 7; 8 x 10, DEFRAMED (Object 7, Box 90)
  - John LeFarge Award from Catholic Interracial Council, 19.5 x 23.5 (Object 8)
  - Civic Service Award, from NY Young Republicans Club, 1962 February 6; 22 x 18.5 (Object 9)
  - first Humanitarian Award for black community work, from the Educational Guild to Mrs. NAR, 1969 November 16; 18.5 x 15.5 (Object 10)
  - FDR Four Freedoms Foundation Award, 1974 April 25; 19 x 21, DEFRAMED (Object 11)
  - Affirmation as Governor, from NY Board of Canvassers, 1962 December 12; 21 x 26, see #s 35, 138, 227 (Object 12)
  - Hon. Anthony W. Daly Award, from Citizens for Educational Freedom, 1965 July 16; 14.5 x 11.5, DEFRAMED (Object 13)
  - Citation of Merit, from village of Lawrence, NY, 1967 January 16; 14 x 11, DEFRAMED (Object 14, Box 90)
  - honorary membership, Young Republican Club of Westchester, NY, 1966 September 6; 14 x 11, DEFRAMED (Object 15)
    DOCUMENT
  - certificate of membership, Hawaii Visitors Bureau, 1961 June 25; 10.5 x 12.5, DEFRAMED (Object 16, Box 90)
  - Certificate of Achievement, National Italo-American War Veterans, 11 x 14, see #119 (Object 17, Box 90)
  - award from Tau Kappa Epsilon, Salem College, 1976 January 26; 11.25 x 14.25 (Object 18, Box 90)
  - honorary citizenship, from Governor of Texas, 1975 November 11; 14.75 x 9.75, see #84, 316 (Object 19, Box 90)
  - Christopher Columbus Award, Knights of Columbus DC chapter, 1953; 14 x 11.5, DEFRAMED (Object 20)
  - Distinguished Service Award in Mental Health, from the Council of the NYC District, of American Psychiatrists' Association, 1967 November 18; 15 x 12, DEFRAMED (Object 21)
  - 2 certificates of appreciation, Syracuse Press Club, 1961, 1962; see #83, 184, 250, 296, 479 (Object 22)
  - framed seal of the Vice President's office, Protective Division, 1975 October 7; 15.25 x 12.25 (Object 23)
  - Award of Appreciation, Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen, 1963 June 15; 14.5 x 11.5, DEFRAMED (Object 24, Box 90)
  - membership to Irish Blackthorn Walking Stick Society, Ireland, 1958 March 17; 11.5 x 9, DEFRAMED (Object 24, Box 90)
  - Bronze Merit Award, from Greater NY Fund, 1961; 16.5 x 12, DEFRAMED (Object 26, Box 90)
  - cruise certificate, from the yacht Sequoia, 1975 July 22; 12 x 14.75, see #458, DEFRAMED (Object 27)
  - Executive Order #76, to rename Empire State Plaza, from Gov. Carey, 1978 October 6; 17.25 x 11 (Object 28)
  - Council of New York City Resolution #480, upon NAR's death, 1979 February 1; 16.5 x 12.5 (Object 29, Box 90)
    Scope and Contents note
    note to Mrs. NAR attached to back
  - membership to American Institute of Architects, 1969 May 7; 11 x 13, DEFRAMED (Object 30, Box 90)
  - Certificate of Commendation, from US Historical Society, 12.25 x 16, DEFRAMED (Object 31)
  - appointment as Fellow in Perpetuity, from the Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1940 January 15; 14 x 15.5, see #796 (Object 32, Box 90)
  - award from Lord and Taylor, 1958; 14 x 16.5, DEFRAMED (Object 33)
  - Citation for Distinguished Service, from Industrial Development magazine, 1951 Ocober 19; 17.75 x 12.75, DEFRAMED (Object 34)
  - Affirmation as Governor, from NY Board of Canvassers, 1970 December 15; 21 x 26, see #s 12, 138, 227 (Object 35)
  - Certificate of Recognition, from Committee for Puerto Rican Day Parade, 1959 May 28; 35.75 x 21.75, DEFRAMED (Object 36)
  - Christmas poem & accompanying statement, from staff at 22 W. 55th St, 1968 December 20; 21 x 17, DEFRAMED (Object 37)
  - endorsement from American Federation of Labor, 8.25 x 10 (Object 38)
    PHOTOGRAPH
  - portrait of NAR sent by "Mr. M.G. Shah, PO Box 783, Aden, Arabia", 17 x 14.25 (Object 39)
  - NAR with President Eisenhower, 12.5 x 14, DEFRAMED (Object 40)
  - Newsweek cover "New Hampshire: Rocky, Barry, or... ?, 1964 March 9; 17 x 14, DEFRAMED (Object 41)
  - NAR w/ LT. Gov. Wilson, Atty. Gen. Lefkowitz, Charles T. Lanigan, originally from C. Lanigan, sent to George L. Hinman, 17 x 21, DEFRAMED (Object 42)
  - NAR with unidentified man, 16.25 x 18.5, DEFRAMED (Object 43)
  - "Education Week" poster-collage of NAR, farms, Venezuela, possibly made by Rosemarie Crane, 1962 January 8; 18 x 22, DEFRAMED (Object 44)
    PICTURE
    w/ note "Files Sylvia Tracey," "To Jim Wicks from Tom Dinnel 6/25"
  - portrait of Urho Kekkonen, President of Finland, 1961 October 18; 10.5 x 8, DEFRAMED (Object 45, Box 90)
  - computer rendering of NAR, possibly from NYS Dept of Transportation, 14.5 x 11.5, DEFRAMED (Object 46)
  - portrait of NAR with Pres. Eisenhower and unidentified at a ceremony, 12 x 13.5, DEFRAMED (Object 47)
  - portrait of NAR with Pres. Eisenhower, 13.5 x 11.5, DEFRAMED (Object 48)
  - portrait of NAR with family, Pres. Eisenhower, and Mrs. Hobby, 12.5 x 14, DEFRAMED (Object 49, Box 90)
  - group shot of NAR with Lt. Gov Wilson, Atty. Gen. Lefkowitz, & Senator Javitz, 5.5 x 7.5, DEFRAMED (Object 50, Box 90)
  - portrait of King Albert II of Belgium, signed, 1963 March; 14.25 x 10.25 (Object 51)
  - NAR w/ Happy amidst a crowd, 14.5 x 11.5 (Object 52)
  - NAR with Pres. Johnson & wife, signed, 14.5 x 12.5 (Object 53)
  - NAR, Ted Agnew, & others in a meeting, marked "Arr. from NYC 7/12/73", 13.5 x 17 (Object 54)
  - NAR w/ General L.L. Lemnitzer at S.H.A.P.E., signed, 1963 October 3; 16.5 x 13.25, DEFRAMED (Object 55, Box 90)
  - NAR w/ Congressman Frank Horton, signed, 13 x 15 (Object 56)
  - portrait of Pres. Johnson with family, signed, 11.75 x 14.75, DEFRAMED (Object 57)
  - portrait of Chairman Bill Miller, signed, 14.75 x 11.75 (Object 58)
  - portrait of Eurico Gaspar Dutra of Brazil, signed, 1943 August 19; 14 x 10, see #653 (Object 59)
  - drawing of NAR by S. Miyagura, sent from Dick Boetan of Staten Island, w/ note from Room 5600, 1970 October 7; 17.25 x 14.25, DEFRAMED (Object 60)
  - drawing of the Capitol Building by John Ross Kev, 11.25 x 15.25, DEFRAMED (Object 61)
  - sketch of NAR by Van Slozza, 18.25 x 13 (Object 62)
  - abstract painting of NAR by Karkam (sp?), 17.25 x 14 (Object 63)
  - painting titled "The Roses: State flower of NY, Iowa, ND, and DC" from Hand Hsiang Chiu Liu, Decatur, GA, 1971 Fall; 18.5 x 22.5, DEFRAMED (Object 64)
  - "In the Arena" quote of Teddy Roosevelt, signed by Earl W. Bridges, 15.5 x 13, see #613 (Object 65)
  - front page of NY Herald Tribune, sent by Jinx & Tex McCrary, 1958 November 5; 25 x 17.25, attached to gold plate w/ Churchill quote (Object 66)
  - 2 Asian designs on paper, from Chase Club Taipei, 21 x 27; both are labeled as #67 (Object 67)
  - 2 Asian designs on paper, from Chase Club Taipei, 21 x 27; both are labeled as #67 (Object 67)
    Conditions Governing Access
  - citation from NY Committee to Employ the Handicapped, 1902 October 28; in large gilded frame (Object 68)
  - painting of a woman in a garden, by Jennie Novik, 1960; 25 x 28.75 (Object 69)
  - "Casa" painting from dedication of Mary Manning Walsh retirement home in NYC, by Anna Altman, age 82, 1969 November 6; 22 x 23, see #780 (Object 70)
  - dreamscape painting of NAR with unicorn, by GOP supporter "Jessica", 1976 February; 17 x 20.5 (Object 71)
  - cubist portrait sent by Hssis Ghafeanhsaif (sp?) "Par Pujba Jungles Friend", 12 x 9.75 (Object 72)
  - pencil drawing of landscape by Mary R., 9.5 x 12.25 (Object 73, Box 90)
  - certificate as Honorary First Citizen, from Watertown NY, 1962 August 24; 10 x 13, DEFRAMED (Object 74, Box 90)
  - Communtiy Theatre Association, 1965 October 9; 18.5 x 13.5 (Object 75)
  - notice of Life Membership in Albany County Women's Republican Club, 1968 January 21; 13 x 16, see #115, 171, DEFRAMED (Object 76)
  - award of Special Honor, from International Narcotic Enforcement Officers Association, 1966 August 28; 17.5 x 14.5, see #1, DEFRAMED (Object 77)
  - NAR and wife with Senator Javits, Jackie Robinson, 5.5 x 7.5, see #50, 195, 391 (Object 78, Box 90)
  - NAR with children, possibly from Rochester Times, 1960 October 22; 14.75 x 12, DEFRAMED (Object 79)
  - portrait of NAR in a car, 13 x 16 (Object 80)
  - portrait of Jsiton Durif Gastnn, from San Salvador, 1945 March 20; 13 x 10.5, DEFRAMED (Object 81, Box 90)
  - NAR with group in front of an Eastern Airlines plane, 14.75 x 13, DEFRAMED (Object 82)
  - Certificate of Appreciation, from National Press Club, D.C., 1976 February 19; 9 x 12, see #22, DEFRAMED (Object 83, Box 90)
  - commission as Honorary Texas Citizen, from Gov. of Texas, 1974 April 1; 14 x 9, see #19, 316 (Object 84, Box 90)
  - honorary degree: Doctor of Law, Columbia University, 1967 June; 17 x 19 (Object 85)
  - Bachelor of Arts Cum Laude degree, Dartmouth College, 1930 September 10; 16 x 19, see # 96, 131-137, 152, 736, 807, 861, 892, 864, 895 (Object 86)
  - certificate from Lincoln School of Teachers College, NYC, 1926 June 4; 14.5 x 15.25, DEFRAMED (Object 87)
    DIPLOMA
  - letter from Mackenzie King declining invite to NAR's wedding, 1930 June 6; 12 x 14.75, see #458, DEFRAMED (Object 88)
    CORRESPONDENCE
  - letter from FDR thanking NAR about Inter-American Affairs work, 1945 March 31; 13.5 x 10 (Object 89)
    "Miss Thompson" written on back
  - letters from Pres. Eisenhower to NAR about a print of Gettysburg, 1953 October 22; 13.5 x 10, letters are back-to-back in frame (Object 90)
  - letter from JDR SR about wedding present to NAR and Mary, 1930 June 13; 12 x 9.75 (Object 91)
  - letter from Abby Rockefeller to NAR, 8.25 x 12 (Object 92)
  - honorary degree: Doctor of Humane Letters, Hamilton College, 1956 June; 18.5 x 20.25 (Object 93)
  - honorary degree: Doctor of Law, Fordham University, 1941 September 17; 17.5 x 21, DEFRAMED (Object 94)
  - honorary degree: Doctor of Law, Jewish Theological Seminary of USA, 1950 November 21; 18.5 x 22 (Object 95)
  - Honorary Doctor of Laws, Dartmouth College, 1957 June 9; 20.25 x 21, see #s 86; DEFRAMED (Object 96)
  - FDR conferring office of Asst. Secretary of State, 1944 December 20; 20 x 24, DEFRAMED, see #5 (Object 97)
  - Diploma de Cidadania, Camara Municipal de Mocaca, 1952 November 16; 24.5 x 20, see # 572, 698, 700 for related (Object 98)
  - Meritorious Service Award, from St. George Assoc. Welfare Chap., 1958 April 13; 12.5 x 10.5 (Object 99)
  - Certificate of Partial Ownership of Fordham ram at Bronx Zoo, 1958 October 31; 13x15 (Object 100)
    from Ram Keepers Class of '59
  - Condolences on NAR's resignation from International Development Advisory, 1951; 20.5 x 15 (Object 101)
  - Decree of Commandeur de la Legion D'Honneur, from France, 1960 April 15; 16.75 x 20.75, see # 509 for medal (Object 102)
  - Honorary Doctor of Law, Yeshiva University, 1958 June; 17.25x21, see #s 345,465,594,869 DEFRAMED (Object 103)
  - photo from NAR Public Service Award Dinner, w/ Happy, Kissinger, Mark Rockefeller, Gerald & Betty Ford, 1991 May 22 (Object 104)
  - 2 scenes of Kykuit: veranda, gardens, statue; fountain, pool and pagoda, 15 x 18 (Object 105)
  - 2 scenes of Kykuit: veranda, gardens, statue; fountain, pool and pagoda, 15 x 18 (Object 105)
    General
  - JDR, possibly signed, 1911; 18.25 x 14.25, DEFRAMED (Object 106)
  - 3 Egyptian artifacts, 15.5 x 19 (Object 107)
  - Aldrich Family Portrait (10 figures), 17.5 x 20.75 (Object 108)
  - White House Fellows Seal, class of 1976-77, 1967-1977; 13.75 x 11.25, DEFRAMED (Object 109)
  - Cartoon about Proposition #1, 16.75 x 12.75, DEFRAMED (Object 110, Box 90)
  - Governor's Code of Fair Practices, w/ NAR signature, 1960 July 15; 17.75 x 14.75 (Object 111)
  - letter from Gov. George Clinton about Pennsylvania militia, with envelope and signed picture, 3 separate pages; DEFRAMED (Object 113)
  - Etching of proposed State Capitol, typed inscription, 1973-1975; 20 x 25, DEFRAMED (Object 114)
  - laminated text of speech from "Religion in American Life" dinner, w/ framed citation from 27th Anniversary, 1976 March 9; wrapped as 2 packages (Object 114)
  - Award for Service, Women's National Republican Club, 1963 January 26; 19.75 x 15.75, see #s 76, 171 (Object 116)
  - Certificate of Membership in the Clipper Club, 1961 July 13; 17 x 18, see #310 same source (Object 116)
  - College Football Centennial Award 1869-1969, from NCAA, 1969 August 28; 15 x 18 (Object 117)
  - U.S. Treasury Dept Award, State of NY, 1961 December; 17.5 x 21.5; DEFRAMED (Object 119)
  - Membership, Italian American War Vets of the US, 1960 August 20; 16.25 x 12.75, see #17 (Object 119)
  - Membership, White Plains Jr. Chamber of Commerce, 1962 October 27; 17 x 14, DEFRAMED (Object 121, Box 90)
  - Honorary Dr. of Humane Letters, NY Medical College, 1966 June 1; 14.25 x 16.25, DEFRAMED (Object 121, Box 90)
  - Report to the Nation, Boy Scouts of America, from anniversary, 1971; 19x15, see #s 169,288,429,476,590,630,635; DEFRAMED (Object 123)
  - Condolences on NAR's death, from SUNY Buffalo, 1979 March 9; 22.5 x 16 (Object 123)
  - Honorary State/Empire Farmer, Future Farmers of American, 1965 January 13; 8.75 x 10.75, see #s 431, 693; DEFRAMED (Object 124, Box 90)
  - tribute to Ford, NAR from Religious Zionists of USA, Jewish National Fund, 1974 September 12; 14.5 x 19.25, DEFRAMED (Object 126)
  - tribute to NAR, from the Utility Club, 1966 May 26-27; 17.5 x 13.5 (Object 127, Box 90)
    w/pamphlet "Rockefeller Record"
  - Award of Recognition, Advertising Women of New York Inc, 1966 May 26; 20 x 15 (Object 128, Box 90)
  - Resolution about actress Helen Hayes, from NAR/Executive Chamber, 1970 March 2; 12.75 x 10, DEFRAMED (Object 128, Box 90)
  - Honorary Citizenship, from Minneapolis, Minnesota, 1959 December 14; 9.25 x 11.25, DEFRAMED (Object 129, Box 90)
  - Bachelor of Hearts Degree, from Pioneer Discussion Group, 1970 September 6; 9.75 x 12.75, DEFRAMED (Object 130, Box 90)
  - Dartmouth College Etchings, artist is Louis Orr, 1932; 18.25 x 13.75, DEFRAMED; see #86 (Object 132)
  - Dartmouth College Etchings, artist is Louis Orr, 1932; 18.25 x 13.75, DEFRAMED; see #86 (Object 133)
  - Dartmouth College Etchings, artist is Louis Orr, 1932; 18.25 x 13.75, DEFRAMED; see #86 (Object 134)
  - Dartmouth College Etchings, artist is Louis Orr, 1932; 18.25 x 13.75, DEFRAMED; see #86 (Object 135)
  - Dartmouth College Etchings, artist is Louis Orr, 1932; 18.25 x 13.75, DEFRAMED; see #86 (Object 136)
  - Dartmouth College Etchings, artist is Louis Orr, 1932; 18.25 x 13.75, DEFRAMED; see #86 (Object 137)
  - Dartmouth College Etchings, artist is Louis Orr, 1932; 18.25 x 13.75, DEFRAMED; see #86 (Object 138)
  - Affirmation as Governor, from State Board of Canvassers, 1962 December 12; 23.5 x 28.5, DEFRAMED; see #12, 35, 227 (Object 139)
  - U.S. Navy Blue Angels, w/ signatures & positions, 1966; 21 x 25 (Object 140)
  - Award for Excellence in the Arts, from Arts Council of Erie, 1976 September 29; 15.5 x 15.25 (Object 140)
  - political cartoon from Harper's Weekly, 1977 March 24; 21 x 16 (Object 142)
  - Award of Merit, NY chapter of American Institute of Architects, 1968 June 5; 24.5 x 18.25, see #155 (Object 142)
  - drawing of St. Patrick's Cathedral, by Alec Stern, 1948 December; 16 x 12, DEFRAMED (Object 143, Box 90)
  - political cartoon by Hy Rosen, signed, 1970; 18 x 14, see # 320 same picture (Object 145)
  - political cartoon, from Charleston Gazette by W. VA campaigners, 1968 July; 18.75 x 15.25, see #223, 224; DEFRAMED (Object 146)
  - presentation of reading from Gov. NAR inauguration, 1959 March 6; 23x21, DEFRAMED (Object 147)
    given by NY Board of Rabbis,
  - painting of mountain top and lake, 23.5 x 29.25; DEFRAMED (Object 149)
  - board from P.S. 121 Nelson A. Rocekfeller Elementary School, with students' signatures, floorplan, and photo, 33.5 x 41.75, DEFRAMED (Object 150)
    school opened 1929 September 9.
  - copy of Emancipation Proclamation, to DDE by NAR, 1962; 25.5 x 45 (Object 151)
    for 100th anniversary. of Proclamation
  - copy of Emancipation Proclamation, to DDE by NAR, 1962; same as #151, w/out inscription (Object 153)
  - appt to Pres.'s Foreign Intelligence Advisory Board, by Nixon, 1969 March 21; 20.5 x 24.5 (Object 154)
  - Honorary Doctor of Law, Syracuse University, 1966 June 5; 20.25 x 25.25 (Object 155)
  - Citation, American Institute of Architects, Board of Directors, 1966 January 27; 21 x 16, see #142, DEFRAMED (Object 156)
  - Public Service Award, Citizens' Housing & Planning Council, NYC, 1967 May 4; 21 x 17 (Object 156)
  - NAR and Nixon in the Oval Office, 16.5 x 19.5 (Object 158)